A Finding Aid to the Allen Tupper True and True Family Papers, 1841-1987, in the Archives of American Art AAA.truealle
Archives of American Art
- Photographs, 1859-1950; Series 9; (boxes 6-7, 1.5 linear ft.)
  - Photograph Album I, undated (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - Photograph Album II, undated (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - 10 Photographs of exhibition installations, undated (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - 5 Photographs of the Panama-Pacific Exposition, 1915 (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - 4 Mexican border travel photographs, undated (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - Pancho Villa and his men, undated (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - 13 England travel photographs, ca. 1905 (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - 20 Europe travel photographs, undated (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - Model posing as Revolutionary War soldier, undated (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - Pueblo architecture (160), (4 folders) (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - Native Americans, (2 folders) (Box 6, Reel 4897)
  - Native Americans, cont., (3 folders) (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Miscellaneous houses, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Miscellaneous towns and settlements, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Miscellaneous saloon interiors, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Cattlemen, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Cowboy models, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Horsemen/Horses, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Rodeos, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Hunters, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Prospectors, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Zoo animals, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Boats/ships, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Wagons/stage coaches/automobiles, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Supply (wagon) trains, undated, (3 folders) (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Lumber industry, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Mining industry, 1909, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Oil wells, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Industrial sites, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Landscapes/plants, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Photographs of artwork by True, Native American themes, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Photographs of artwork by True, Cowboy/settler themes, undated, (3 folders) (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Photographs of artwork by True, Miscellaneous works by True, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Photographs of artwork by Frank Brangwyn, 1913, undated (Box 7, Reel 4897)
  - Photographs of miscellaneous works by others, 1930, undated; (5 folders) (Box 7, Reel 4897)
- Scrapbook, 1934; Series 10; (box 7, 1 volume)
  - Scrapbook containing clippings of newspaper serial of Charles Dickens' "The Life of Our Lord,", 1934 (Box 7, Reel 4898)
- Printed Material, 1875-1981; Series 11; (box 7, 10 folders)
  This series includes clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs for True and for others, reproductions of works, programs, booklets, and miscellaneous items.
  - Clippings, 1879-1981; (10 folders) (Box 7, Reel 4898)
  - Exhibition announcements and catalogs for True, 1908-1980 (Box 7, Reel 4898)
  - Exhibition announcements and catalogs for others, undated, 1908 (Box 7, Reel 4898)
  - Reproductions of works of art by True, undated (Box 7, Reel 4898)
  - Christmas cards designed by True, undated (Box 7, Reel 4898)
  - Programs, 1875-1950 (Box 7, Reel 4898)
  - Brochures, 1921-1939 (Box 7, Reel 4898)
  - Constitutions and by-laws for the Architectural League of New York and the National Society of Mural Painters, 1931, 1936 (Box 7, Reel 4898)
  - Booklets: "One Hundred Years of the Locomotive," "Art in Denver," and "The Rights of Man" by Harold Laski, 1916-1940 (Box 7, Reel 4898)
  - Picture postcards, undated (Box 7, Reel 4898)
  - Miscellaneous printed material, undated, 1950 (Box 7, Reel 4898)
- Artifacts, ca. 1863; Series 12; (box 10, 9 items)
  This series includes the following: five bullets and fragments, 2 buttons, a small piece of marble, and a fragment of a flat wooden stick that have not been microfilmed. They were housed together and accompanied by three notes reading: "Found by Henry on Look Out Mtn on Oct 1898 where the battle above the clouds was fought in 1863;" "Springfield rifle balls, Spanish American War;" and "Found on Chickamauga battlefield." Also found are the following, which have not been filmed:The following artifacts have not been microfilmed: a pocket knife with initials "FET;" two small pocket compasses; a metal badge saying "Columbian Exposition, 1893;" and a small, undecorated metal disk.
  - Artifacts, ca. 1863 (Box 10 (sol), Reel 4898)
- Glass Plate Negatives, undated; Series 13; (boxes 8-9, 0.8 linear ft.)
  Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
  - Allen Tupper True, undated (Box 8, Reel unfilmed)
    1 glass plate negative
  - Paintings of Cowboys, undated (Box 8, Reel unfilmed)
    7 glass plate negatives
  - Paintings of Settlers, undated (Box 8, Reel unfilmed)
    2 glass plate negatives
  - Paintings of Native Americans, undated (Box 8, Reel unfilmed)
  - Murals, undated (Box 8, Reel unfilmed)
    9 glass plate negatives
  - Mural from Montana National Bank, undated (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
  - Warren Branch Library Mural, undated (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
  - American Theatre Murals, undated (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    4 glass plate negatives
  - Colorado National Bank Murals, undated (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
  - Denver Civic Center Murals, undated (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
  - Denver Public Library Mural, undated (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)